I'm about to show you how to give your
open claw superpowers. You need to build
a mission control inside your Open Claw.
And in this video, I'll show you how to
do it in just a couple of prompts.
Mission control is a custom dashboard
for your OpenClaw that allows it to
build any tool it needs on the fly. In
this video, I'll take you through my
entire mission control setup, every tool
I use, and show you how to set up your
own in just a couple of prompts. Zero
programming experience needed, zero
technical experience needed. If you
stick with me until the end, I promise
your open claw is going to be a hundred
times more powerful no matter who you
are. Let's get into it. If you're
wondering about the different
background, I'm reporting in straight
from Shabuya. I'm going to take you
through every critical mission control
tool I have. This is my mission control.
I truly believe everyone, no matter who
you are, if you are using Open Claw, you
need to be using mission control. This
makes it so much better and also just a
lot more fun to use. This is completely
custom. This is a completely custom
dashboard. All the tools you see on the
lefth hand side were all built by my
open claw. Nothing is out of the box.
Nothing was downloaded from the web. All
custom built and I didn't write a single
line of code. The open claw made all of
it. So here's what I'm going to do. I'm
going to take you through every mission
control tool. You need to have your open
claw build. These will be relevant to
everyone. I'm not going to go through
every tool on the lefth hand side. Some
of them are still experimental that I'm
building out. We'll do follow-up videos
with those. But the ones that work that
are great and everyone should have them,
I'm about to show you. And these were
all built simply from me going to my
open claw and saying, "Hey, build me out
a tool in my mission control that does
this or build me out a tool in my
mission control that shows my calendar
or shows me what tasks I'm working on."
Just one simple prompt and it was all
built. If you'd like to build this out
side by side with me as I go through all
my tools, feel free to pause right now.
go to your OpenClaw and say, "Hey, I
want my own mission control where we can
build custom tools. Please build it in
Nex.js and host it on the local host."
Once you do that, it will build a
template. You can also say make it a
clean interface that looks like linear
and you'll get a mission control that's
as beautiful as this. So, let's go into
it. Let's go into all the critical tools
you need in your mission control. As you
go, feel free to pause and describe each
tool and your open claw will do it. So,
I want to start off on the task board. I
think this is a critical critical tool.
This taskboard makes it so easy for me
to track everything my Open Claw is
doing. I can see what Henry's working
on. I can see what Henry's sub agents
are working on. I'm always on top of
what they're doing. This solves a lot of
problems. This solves the biggest
problem where people go, "Oh, I don't
know what my open claw is doing. I don't
know what it completed. I don't know if
it's halfway done tasks." You don't have
visibility into what your open claw did.
Now, with this task board, you know
everything your open claw is doing and
what it's accomplished. So you can see
here it is a simple cananband board
where every task is on here is assigned
to either me or Henry. You can see the A
is for me, the H is for Henry. It shows
a description of the task and really
important is over on the left hand side
is a live activity feed which allows me
to see every single thing Henry is doing
in detail. So this just allows me to
confirm Henry is doing the work he's
saying he's doing. As Henry does the
work, he moves the tasks over on the
board towards the right until it's done.
Anything that needs to be reviewed by me
is right in review and I can go and just
approve it. Just a great way to manage
and track everything your open claw
does. If you need to add new tasks, you
can hit new task and if you assign it to
Henry or your openclaw, your open claw
will automatically find that and do the
task for you. What I did was I asked my
openclaw that in every heartbeat check
our task board, see if any tasks are
assigned to my openclaw in the backlog
and then do any tasks that are assigned
to them. So, every heartbeat is checking
this task board to see if any tasks are
assigned and getting it done
autonomously. This increased my
efficiency and also just keeps me on top
of whatever Henry is doing. Make sure to
build this task board. Just describe
what I showed to you and your agent will
build it for you. No coding at all. The
next screen I want to show you is one of
the most important ones I'll show you.
This is the calendar screen. And the
reason why this is so powerful is it
shows you what cron jobs and what tasks
you have scheduled for your open claw.
One of the biggest complaints I get
about OpenClaw is that it's not
proactive enough. That it's not doing
proactive tasks for the users. This
allows you to confirm that your OpenClaw
is being proactive. Whenever you say,
"Hey, do something for me at night. Do
something for me every morning. Do
something productive every afternoon."
You can come to your calendar screen and
see and confirm that your open claw
scheduled those cron jobs to do those
tasks. There's an issue I've been seeing
with people. Some open clauses, they
say, "Hey, I'll do that for you." and
then they never actually do those
things. This calendar is a great way to
confirm it. And this also puts you and
your open claw on the same page where
you can say after scheduling a task,
hey, you said you scheduled a task, but
I don't see it on the calendar. Now
you're open go confirm it's on the
calendar and make sure it's actually
scheduling its own tasks. The more you
use OpenClaw, the more scheduled tasks
you'll have. This helps you stay on top
of all of them and make sure your
OpenClaw is being proactive. ask for it
to build a calendar for you that shows
all the crown jobs and scheduled tasks
it have and you will have an amazing
screen like this. Next is the project
screen. So this is a really good one for
tracking every project you're working
on. It's very easy to get distracted
with Open Claw, play around, build
things you don't really need and not
stay on top of the tasks that actually
move the ball forward. This project
screen is good for that. You go in here,
have your open claw build a project for
every single major project you have
going on in your life. And now when you
get scatterbrained, you can come back
into this project screen. See how close
you are to completing those projects and
go and pay attention to the ones that
maybe you haven't worked on in a while.
Right? If I'm looking at this, I might
want to go, okay, I want to build out
the AI extension for my school. By the
way, Vibe Coding Academy live boot camps
every single Friday in that. Sign up for
that down below. I did an entire
two-hour boot camp on this mission
control. You get instant access to that.
Anyway, the project screen, which you
see here, is just a great way to make
sure every single day you're progressing
on the major high lever tasks you're
working on. And what's great is this
hooks into all my other screens. So, I'm
about to show you a lot of really cool
things in a second when it comes to
memories and documents, but this allows
you to hook in task, memories, documents
to every project you're working on. Just
an amazing way to stay organized.
And a little bonus tip here, this is a
great way to go and reverse prompt your
open claw and say something like, "Hey,
what's one task we can do right now that
will help us progress in one of our
major projects?" And it will come up
with tasks to do that help you advance
in these projects. So great reverse
prompting opportunity. I talk about
reverse prompting all the time, asking
your open claw questions. Great reverse
prompting opportunity on this screen,
too. Have to make a project screen. And
if you don't know which projects you're
working on, that's fine, too. Go to your
openclaw reverse prompt. If you were to
categorize five projects we're working
on right now, openclaw, what would you
say those five projects are? And it will
figure them out for you. You don't even
have to think. Whenever you get
confused, reverse prompt. Next is the
memory screen. This is a critical
critical tool to implement. One of the
best parts about OpenClaw is its memory
system. It has an amazing memory system
where it remembers basically all your
conversations from every single day. One
thing I like to do often is go back and
go through those memories almost like a
journal entry and see what we talked
about on certain days. Or if I'm working
on something and I forget details of
past conversations, I can come back and
look at past memories, too. That's all
done on this memory screen. Typically,
your memories are stuck in a unorganized
memories.mmarkdown file that's really
hard to find and read. This makes it
really easy to find any past memories,
organize them, and almost read them like
a journal. I can't wait 10 years from
now when I can go back, look at what I
was talking about with Henry from 10
years ago, see what we're working on,
see what we're talking about, and
basically just use these memories as a
tracker of my entire life. That's what
this memory screen allows you to do. So,
what you want to do is you want to go
into your open claw. I want a memory
screen in our mission control that
allows me to view every memory you have
organized by day. Build that out for me,
please. and also have a long-term memory
document that allows me to see all the
long-term memories we have as well. This
is just great for finding old thoughts
and old conversations you were having
and seeing what you were talking about
on specific days. It's basically a
record of your entire digital life. It's
amazing. Build the memory screen just
for pure organization sake. This next
screen I'm going to talk about is
extremely important. It's very similar
to memories, but equally, if not more
important, and that is the doc screen.
If you're anything like me, your open
claw is constantly building you docs,
planning docs, architecture docs,
product requirement docs. It's writing
you newsletters. It's writing you
content and just writing a whole bunch
of things for you. Unfortunately, that
usually lives in your chat. So, if you
want to find an old document, you have
to scroll back in your chat in your
Telegram or Discord for a while, but not
with this doc screen. This doc screen is
so so helpful. every doc your open claw
creates goes into this doc screen and
allows you to go back and see every
document it's created in a really nicely
formatted way. So for instance, every
Thursday I have my open claw write me my
newsletter I'm going to send out. I
don't just send out straight with
whatever my openclaw wrote, but I use it
as a first draft. So when I go back and
I want to send out my newsletter, I can
go in here. I can search for the draft
of the newsletter. I can copy and paste
this newsletter draft into Substack,
edit it myself, and then send it out
instead of having to scroll back for 10
minutes to find this draft. Everything
is just stored in this documents tool.
And what's great is it automatically
categorizes it, shows me what formats
each document is in. It's really
organizable. And I can even search. So,
if I want to see which files have Mac
Studio mentioned in it, because I do a
bunch of Mac Studio planning with all my
computers, I can just search for it and
find those documents really, really
easily. Go to your open claw and say, I
want a docs tool where I can go back and
view all the previous documents you
created for me in a nicely formatted
view. Make it searchable and categorize
the documents. If you put in that
prompt, you'll have an amazing documents
tool ready to go. I have two more tools
to show you that I'm going to show you
how to actually find which custom tools
you need to build for yourself that I
haven't shown here. If you learned
anything so far, make sure to leave a
like down below. Subscribe and turn on
notifications. Every person that turns
on notifications will be another piece
of sushi I eat here in Japan. This next
screen is my favorite. I think it is the
most important. It keeps your OpenClaw
agent on task with one mission in mind
and keeps it organized with all its sub
agents it's working with and that is the
team screen. This team screen shows me
every agent I have spun up, every sub
aent it uses, what their roles are and
our mission statement. This is like our
org structure for the digital company
we're running. So at the top you can see
the main open claw Henry what his role
is and then we can see all the other
open claws and sub aents we've spun up.
It shows what devices they're on. It
shows what roles they have. Right? I
have Charlie who's my engineer. This is
run by Quen locally on my Mac Studio. We
have Ralph. This is powered by Chad GBT.
We have all the different sub aents. And
then we have the lowest level worker
agents. This helps keep my agents
organized where they know who to spin up
and who to give work to. Again, another
place that's kind of the record of truth
where if an agent gets confused or
doesn't remember who should be working
on what, it can go to the team screen,
say, "Oh, okay. I got to give this to
Charlie for development. I got to give
this Violet for research." And it helps
keep all your agents organized. By the
way, if you want a follow-up video on
when you should use sub agents versus
open clause, let me know down below. I
could make that my next video if there's
enough demand for that. But a really
important part of the screen as well is
the mission statement, which I put at
the top here. You should have a mission
statement for your open claw. This is
the mission everyone is working towards
at the same time. This makes it so
whenever your open claws come up with
tasks to work on, they ensure that there
are tasks that bring you closer to your
goals and ambitions. So for me, my
mission statement is I want to build an
autonomous organization of AI agents
that do work for me and produce value
247. Everything we do, I want to get
closer to that. And the best part is is
I can use reverse prompting here. So
when my agents are idle, I can say,
"What task can we do right now that
brings us closer to our mission
statement?" You want a mission statement
as well. If you don't know what you're
working towards with your open clause,
reverse prompt based on everything you
know about me. What should be our
mission statement? That will give you a
mission statement you can work towards
and it makes it so all the proactive
tasks your open clause do brings you
closer to that goal. Lastly, I want to
talk about the office screen. And you
might see this and go, "What the hell is
this? Do I really need this? Is there
any point to this?" The answer to all
those questions is yes, you do need
this. And there is a point to this. This
is a visual that shows me what all my
agents are working on. So, as my agents
work, they'll go to their different
screens. They'll go to the desk.
Sometimes they'll even talk to each
other and meet around the water cooler.
This is a great place to track what your
agents are doing. If I need to confirm
my agent's actually doing something at
any given moment, I can come here and
see if they're working on their computer
and see what they're actually working
on, too. Here's an important point I
want to make here is when using
OpenClaw, it is critical, critical,
critical you have fun. There is nothing
wrong with having fun when you use
OpenClaw. Nothing at all. I like to have
fun. This is really fun for me. This
makes me want to come back to my open
claw more and do more work and get more
done just cuz it's a fun thing to do.
Not everything has to be a boring CLI.
It could be an actual fun 2D interface
where you watch agents walk around and
do work. What I would do is I'd go to
your OpenClaw, say, "Hey, I want a
screen that visualizes all the work
you're doing. I want a 2D pixel art
office that shows you and all the sub
agents. I want them to have desks and
when they are doing work, they go to
their desk and actually do the work." If
you put that prompt in, it will build
something similar to this. If you want,
you can even pause here and screenshot
this. any screen I showed you so far,
feel free to screenshot it and give it
to your open claw, and it will build it
to look like whatever I built. You can
also just take the link for this video,
too, and give it to your open claw.
It'll find the transcript and build out
everything I said. That's that's
probably the easiest way for you to use
this video. But here's a really
important note I want to make on
everything I showed you so far. I don't
want you to just straight up copy me.
It's not that I care if people copy me.
You can copy anything I do. I don't
care. But the reason why I think you
should avoid copying me is because this
is a hyperpersonalized
for you dashboard. The tools should all
be useful for you. You shouldn't just
take other people's tools, put them in,
and then use their workflows. No two
people's workflows are the same. So,
it's important you come up with your own
custom tools. How do you do that? Well,
the answer is probably not going to
surprise you. Reverse prompting. After
you build out the initial version of
your mission control, you should go in
and reverse prompt your open claw based
on what you know about me, what we've
done, our workflows, our mission
statement, our goals. What custom tools
should we build out in our mission
control? What that'll do is cause your
open claw to think for a while and come
up with the custom tools you need to
make your workflows easier. This will
build custom tools that are way more
relevant for whatever you're doing than
anything I show you. You can copy me. I
don't care. Go ahead, copy whatever you
want. But I think the most important
exercise you can do right now is reverse
prompt and find the tools that are
custom for you. And again, everything
I've talked about in this video, you can
just copy and paste the link for this
YouTube say, "Hey, OpenClaw, check this
out." And it will actually go and get
the transcript and really build all this
out for you and say, "Hey, is there
anything in this video we haven't done
yet?" and it will go and do it for you.
So, make sure to do that as well. If you
learned anything at all, please leave a
like down below, subscribe, turn
notifications. Also, I do live boot
camps every single week in the Vibe
Coding Academy. Feel free to join and
ask me questions. You can talk to me
live in there. Link for that down below.
Hope you enjoyed this. Way more videos
coming soon, especially when I get back.
and I'll see you in the next